Stephen L. Weber Papers
State University of New York at Oswego
Stephen L. Weber Papers
1988 - 1996
Dr. Stephen L. Weber worked to enhance faculty development, foster diversity and intercultural competence, make the campus more self-sufficient, improve service to the community, and enrich the natural and cultural environment of the campus. Weber saw the continued expansion of student numbers and academic offerings -- spearheading the creation the School of Business and the current version of the School of Education in 1992 from the Division of Professional Studies.
1 linear foot
Weber, Stephen L.
State University of New York at Oswego Penfield Library 7060 State Route 104 Oswego, New York 13126-3599
2001.013.0001
Collection is open to the public.
Dr. Stephen L. Weber was president of SUNY Oswego from 1988 - 1996. Dr. Weber was Vice President for Academic Affairs, St. Cloud University, St. Cloud, Minnesota, from 1984-1988. He was the Dean of Arts and Sciences, Fairfield University from 1979-1984. He was assistant to the President, University of Maine from 1976 - 1979. Dr. Weber was an associate professor of Philosophy, Fairfield University; associate professor of philosophy, University of Maine; and graduate assistant in honors, University of Colorado.
Dr. Weber received a Ph.D. in Philosophy from the University of Notre Dame in 1969; graduate studies in Philosophy and Classics, University of Colorado, 1964-66; Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, Bowling Green State University, 1964.
Dr. Weber's scholarly works include being executive producer of "Paul Cadmus: Enfant Terrible at 80", 1984. Articles by Dr. Weber have been published in Liberal Education, Journal of Social Philosophy, The Philosophical Reflection of Man in Literature, Review of Metaphysics, The New Scholasticism and The Journal of Religion.
Dr. Weber is married to Susan Keim Weber and they have two sons, Richard L. Weber and Matthew K. Weber.
Dr. Weber worked to enhance faculty development, foster diversity and intercultural competence, make the campus more self-sufficient, improve service to the community, and enrich the natural and cultural environment on the campus.
Hostos, Eugenio María de, 1839-1903; State University College (Oswego, N.Y.); Milley, Jane E.; Monette, Paul; Van Schaack, Herbert; Johnstone, D. Bruce (Donald Bruce), 1941-; Pan Am Flight 103; Rice, Harvey Mitchell, 1907-1992; College presidents; Furfaro, Francis J., Reverend; Johnson, Nan; Koenig, George H.; Lee-Clark, Mary H., Reverend; Richmond, David; Sheldon, E. A. (Edward Austin), 1823-1897; Shenandoah, Audrey; Sullivan, John T., Jr.; Torchlight Ceremony -- New York -- Oswego; Sheldon Society -- New York -- Oswego; Shady Shore -- New York -- Oswego; Convocation -- New York -- Oswego; Speeches; Inauguration; Clark, James M.
Papers include correspondence, memorandums, inaugural materials, budget information, five year plan, speeches, videotapes and audio tapes concerning the presidential term of Dr. Stephen L. Weber during his years at SUNY Oswego from 1988 to 1996.
These papers were accessioned at earlier dates, but are now combined to form one collection under the new (1999) archival scheme. Information dealing with renovation projects and inventories at Shady Shore (the President's house), the Sheldon Family (including its 1991 reunion on campus), correspondence from descendants of Japanese student Hideo Takamine, and copies of letter written in 1937-38 from Marian Mahar have been removed and placed in more appropriate record groups.
- Inauguration materials, n.d. (Box-folder 01-01)
  Inauguration materials include lists of events, 2 Thank you cards+, Speech by Father Furfarro, Benediction given by Reverend Mary H. Lee-Clark, Memo to faculty and staff from Herbert Van Schaack, Speech by President James M. Clark, SUNY Cortland (2 pages), Correspondence pertaining to speech by Mrs. Nan Johnson, Speech by Chancellor D. Bruce Johnstone (3 pages), Speech by Mayor John T. Sullivan, Jr. (3 pages), Correspondence accepting invitations and declining invitations, Thank yous from Dr. Weber regarding the Inauguration and items sent to him, Inaugurations Week Timetable and Guidelines for Inaugurations of Campus Presidents State University of New York, Inauguration Addresses, Thank you lists, Inaugural Remarks by Dr. Stephen L. Weber, President
- Inauguration Program & Invitation, 1989 (Box-folder 01-02)
  2 invitation with response cards to the inauguration of Dr. Stephen L. Weber, Ninth President of SUNY Oswego. 4 programs for the 1989 inauguration.
- Inauguaration armbands & ribbons, 1989 (Box-folder 01-03)
  3 yellow and green armbands with SUCO emblem. 10 ribbons commemorating Dr. Stephen Weber's inauguration.
- Inauguration cassette tapes, 1989 (Box-folder 01-04)
  4 cassette tapes, "The Inauguration of Dr. Stephen Weber, April 28, 1989".
- Speeches, 1989 (Box-folder 01-05)
  2 speeches given by Dr. Weber May 19, 1989 Torchlight remarks (2 pages) and 128th Commencement May 20, 1989. Speech reflecting the special contributions of students Collen Brunner & Lynn Harunian who were onboard Pan Am Flight 103. New student convocation remarks. Remarks to faculty. Correspondence and speech to Camden Central School district. Affirmative action remarks. University /community cooperation and mutual development speech. Remarks to the Rotary. Transcript of video expressing support for campus campaign against bias. Remarks to students "BE A BIAS BUSTER". December Commencement speech.
- Speeches, 1990 (Box-folder 01-06)
  Martin Luther King Jr. celebration. Women Aloud. Honors Convocation. 129th Commencement. Scholarship Banquet A.M.E. Zion Church. Organizational change. Touchlight Remarks. Faculty Breakfast Remarks. Student Convocation- Remarks to Students. Welcome to Fourth Annual Multi-Cultural Student Reception. Remarks to students. Central Square Remarks. Faculty/Alumni Board Meeting. Charge to Full Professors. December Commencement.
- Speeches, 1991 (Box-folder 01-07)
  General Faculty Remarks. Martin Luther King Jr. Celebration. Remarks to General Faculty. Submission to LIBERAL EDUCATION publication. Quest Honors Ceremony. Remarks to General Faculty. Torchlight ceremony remarks. 130th Commencement. WSGO Radio spot- "Historical Notes" Autumn remarks to students. General Faculty remarks. Minnesota Systems of Appropriations. Remarks to Rotary. "Working Smarter" remarks to Faculty/Professional Staff. Restructuring. December Commencement.
- Speeches, 1992 (Box-folder 01-08)
  Martin Luther King Jr. speech. Student Rally Speech. Leadership in Times of Crisis. Oswego County Historical Minute. Economic Impact breakfast speech. Public Programs on Aging - Dr. Richar J. Ham speaker. Economic Impact Presentation County Legislature. General Faculty Remarks. Speech on Father Hall. Torchlight Toast. Torchlight Remarks. 131st Commencement. Employee Recognition Luncheon. School Partnerships Speech. Sithe Energies Rally. Reunion Dinner remarks. Remarks to Alumni. State of the College. Freshman Rally Speech. World of Music. Remarks to D.E.C. Superintendents Conference. Technology Meeting speech. International Management Council. Torchlight remarks. December Commencement AM/PM.
- Speeches, 1993 (Box-folder 01-09)
  Remarks to the Faculty. ;"The Path Ahead, Remarks to the Faculty" (6 pages); "World of Music: Creating a Musical Personality". (10 pages); "Remarks to Leadership Oswego County." (14 pages); Remarks for LEAD Center, "The Politics of Professional Survival". (8 pages); Remarks to Fulton Chamber of Commerce. (5 pages); Spring Honors Ceremony Remarks. (2 pages); Open House Remarks. (2 pages); "Reflections". (2 pages); "Refuting the Case Against Gays in the Military". (7 pages); Remarks to University Faculty Senate. (2 pages); Matter of Making this a Multicultural Community; Remarks to General Faculty; Torchlight Toast (3 pages);132 Commencement; Remarks for Alumni Reunion.; Accelerating Pace of Change (2 pages) Team Sheldon Retreat. (4 pages) Torchlight remarks. (3 pages); Fall Remarks to the Faculty. (9 pages); SUNY OSWEGO: Pioneering Excellence for the 21st Century; "World of Music: Creating a Musical Personality". (2 pages) Alumni Barbecue Thank You Comments; Essay Liberal Education & Human Liberation for publication in EDUCATIONAL RECORD Civil Liberities Presentation Correspondence from Federal Judical Center to Dr. Weber to publish paper on mentoring. School of Education Convocation. (2 pages) Charge to Full Professors. (1 page) Correspondence to Dr. Weber from Merrilee Witherell (participating in "Dirty Books & Dangerous Ideas". "State University of New York at Oswego Stategic Plan Phase I: 'Vision and Critical Issues'". (17 pages) December Commencement
- Speeches, 1994 - 1996 (Box-folder 01-10)
  1994: Financial Aid Awareness Month remarks. (2 pages) "World of Music: Creating a Musical Personality". (10 pages) Martin Luther King speech. (1 page) Society for Human Resource Management. (3 pages) Open House. (2 pages) Spring Honors Ceremony Remarks. (2 pages) Torchlight Toast. (1 page) Torchlight Remarks. (3 pages) AM SPEECH: 133rd Commencement Division of Arts and Sciences speech. (4 pages) PM SPEECH: 133rd Commencement School of Business and School of Education speech. Youth Recognition Speech. (1 page) Schooner Launching. (2 pages) Sheldon Society Dinner Theater. (3 pages) August - Torchlight Remarks. (3 pages) "Faculty Governance and Organizational Change: An Oxymoron?" (2 pages) "SUNY Oswego: A Moment of Opportunity". (10 pages) "A Moment of Opportunity, Fall Remarks to Faculty and Professional Staff". September - "World of Music: Creating a Musical Personality". (2 pages) "Governance Speech: Address to General Faculty". (10 pages) "The Promise of Diversity Address to the Rotary Club of Syracuse" "Remarks to Leadership Oswego County". (14 pages) October - Charge to Full Professors. (1 page) November - College of Arts and Sciences First Lecture. (2 pages) Remarks to School of Education. (2 pages) Remarks for Roundtable. (5 pages) December Commencement. (4 pages) n.d. - David Richmond Memorial. (3 pages) - Eugenio Maria de Hostos. (3 pages) - Jane Milley Introduction. (1 page)
  1995: Teaching of Values in Universities; Reinventing Excellence Remarks to Faculty Assembly Boutwell Award Explorations in Research Penny Wise & Pound Foolish Changing Values Marting Luther King Banquet Presentatin of 1995 President's Award for Creative & Scholarly Activity & Research and Awards for Excellence in Sponsored Research Remarks for the Lead Center Report on The Five Year Plan Dear Graduates AM: 134 Commencement PM: 134 Commencement Remarks at Schenectady County Community College Internatinal Energy Conference
  1996: Remarks to Oswego Faculty & Staff (5/2/96)
- Correspondence, 1988 (Box-folder 01-11)
  1988 correspondence from Harvey M. Rice (SUNY Oswego president, 1947-1951) to Stephen L. Weber responding to a gift of Dorothy Roger's book from Dr. Weber.
- Plans, 1989 - 1993 (Box-folder 01-12)
  1989 "Proposed Five - Year Plan for SUNY Oswego". (12 pages) 2 copies. Second copy includes memorandum from George Koenig, 2 page comments on Five - Year plan and handwritten notes. "Preparing for the 21st Century: Report On The Five - Year Plan, SUNY Oswego, 1989-94" by Stephen L. Weber, April, 1995. (20 pages) 2 copies. "State University of New York at Oswego Strategic Plan Phase I, August 1993". Draft. (18 pages) Includes memorandum from Dr. Weber. 2 copies. "State University of New York at Oswego Strategic Plan Phase I: 'Vision and Critical Issues'". (17 pages) 2 copies. Includes memorandum from Long Range Planning Coordinating Committee, November, 1993. Also included is a 4 page questionnaire concerning cirriculum and college concerns to be returned to Deborah Stanley. 4 page letter to Friends of SUNY Oswego from Dr. Weber concerning the five-year plan, 1990. SUNY Oswego organizational chart 1988-1989. SUNY Oswego organizational chart 1993.
- Luncheon Cruise, 1989 (Box-folder 01-13)
  2 invitations and a memorandum concerning the 1989 luncheon cruise hosted by Dr. & Mrs. Weber and the Oswego Alumni Association.
- Memorandums, 1989 - 1995 (Box-folder 01-14)
  23 memorandums and correspondence from Dr. Weber to faculty, staff, college community and friends of SUNY Oswego. Subjects include budgets, councils and committees, charity donations, college enrollment, power outage, resignations, appointments, etc. December, 1995, correspondence to the Oswego Campus Community from Dr. Weber announces his resignation in 1996.
- Budget Materials, 1989 - 1995 (Box-folder 01-15)
  11 memorandums from Dr. Weber concerning budgets. Includes budget briefings, press releases and state budget excerpts. Also included is a pamphlet, "SUNY Oswego, Facts & Figures".
- Commencements, 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 01-16)
  Papers include memorandums, speeches and a newspaper clippings regarding SUNY Oswego commencements, 1992 - 1993. Includes: 4 page speech, December, 1993. 4 page welcoming speech for the School of Business and School of Education Commencement, May, 1993. 4 page welcoming speech to the Division of Arts and Sciences Commencement, May, 1993 3 page address by Paul Monette, May, 1992 (2 copies). 2 copies of speech by Audrey Shenandoah, May, 1992 and a newspaper clipping.
- Presidential Search Committee, 1988 (Box-folder 01-17)
  Includes 2 copies of memorandums to "Recepient of Credentials for Presidential Candidate" from the Presidential Search Committe, 1988. Attached to these memorandums is a copy of Dr. Weber's vita. Also included is a letter from Dr. Weber with attachments in response to inquiries from the search committee. Photocopy of The Oswegonian article, "College Council chooses St. Cloud's Weber", April 1988.
- Videotapes, 1989 - 1990 (Box-folder 01-18)
  3 videotapes include the inauguration of President Weber, 1990 Arts & Sciences commencement and farewell video. Also included are 2 wooden plaques with brass plates attached, "President Inauguration, State University of New York, Oswego, Stephen L. Weber, Ninth President, April 28, 1989.
- Congratulatory certificate from Northeastern University, 1989 (Box-folder 02-01)
  Bound certificate - "The President, Trustees and Faculty of Northeastern University extend cordial greetings and congratulations to State University of New York at Oswego on the occasion of the inauguration of Stephen L. Weber as the Ninth President and send best wishes for continued success and distinguished educational achievement. Given at Boston, Massachusetts, this twenty-eighth day of April in the year of Our Lord, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine and of Northeastern University, in its ninety-first year." Signed Kenneth G. Ryder, President.
- Congratulatory certificate from North Adams State College, 1989 (Box-folder 02-02)
  Bound congratulatory certificate from North Adams State College. "The Board of Trustees, President, Faculty, Staff and Alumni of North Adams State College extend their heartiest congratulations to State University of New York / Oswego upon the happy occasion of the inauguration of Stephen L. Weber as the ninth president of the college on the 28th day of April, 1989. Given at North Adams, Massachusetts this 14th day of April, 1989" Signed Catherine A. Tisinger, President.
- Congratulatory certificate from Indiana University of Pennsylvania, 1989 (Box-folder 02-03)
  Bound congratulatory certificate from Indiana University of Pennsylvania. "The Council of Trustees, The President, and The Faculty of Indiana University of Pennsylvania send Greetings and Congratulations to The State University of New York at Oswego on the occasion of the inauguration of Stephen L. Weber as President. March 15, 1989. Indiana, Pennsylvania." Signed John D. Welty, President.
- Congratulatory certificate from Brooklyn College, 1989 (Box-folder 02-04)
  Bound congratulatory certificate from Brooklyn College. "The President, Faculty, Staff and Students of Brooklyn College of The City University of New York Extend Congratulations and Best Wishes to Stephen L. Weber on his Inauguration as President of State University of New York at Oswego". Signed Robert L. Hess, President. "Dated this twenty-eighth day of April Nineteen hundred and eighty nine."
- Congratulatory certificate from University at Albany State University of New York, 1989 (Box-folder 02-05)
  Bound congratulatory certificate from University at Albany State University of New York. "The President, the members of the University Council, and the Faculties of the University at Albany State University of New York wish to extend cordial greetings and best wishes to Stephen L. Weber on the occasion of his inauguration as ninth President of the State University of New York at Oswego on this day, the twenty-eighth of April, nineteen eighty-nine." Signed Vincent O'Leary, President.
- Congratulatory certificate from The University of Connecticut, 1989 (Box-folder 02-06)
  Bound congratulatory certificate from The University of Connecticut. "The Trustees, President, and Faculty of The University of Connecticut extend congratulations and cordial greetings to State University of New York at Oswego on the occasion of The Inauguration of Stephen L. Weber as President with best wishes for continued progress and educational achievement. April 28, 1989."
- Congratulatory certificates from Tufts University + Saint Joseph's University, Philadelphia, 1989 (Box-folder 02-07)
  Congratulatory certificates from Tufts University + Saint Joseph's University, Philadelphia.
  "Tufts University to State University of New York at Oswego on the occasion of the Inauguration of Stephen L. Weber as Ninth President of the College Tufts University sends felicitations on this occasion and best wishes for continued distinguished achievement. Given at Medford, Massachusetts, on this 23rd day of March in the year of our Lord, nineteen hundred and eighty-nine and of Tufts University, the one hundred and thirty-seventh."
  "The Board of Directors, President, and Faculty of Saint Joseph's University, Philadelphia Extend Greetings and Congratulations to State University of New York at Oswego on the Occasion of the Inauguation of Dr. Stephen L. Weber as President. Given at Philadelphia, Pennsylvania this 9th day of March 1989." Signed Reverend Nicholas S. Rashford, S.J., President.